Nemuel M Gabitanan Jr

Quezon City, Metro Manila | 0977-103-2610 | nemuelmgabitananjr@gmail.com

PROFILE

A career-shifter from a longtime Back-Office agent to a Web Developer returning to my roots as a programmer same from college days. Engaged in a Full-Stack Web-developer bootcamp to be refreshed and be proficient again in an assortment of technologies, including HTMI/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, and aquired bootcamp knowledge like Bootstrap 5, Jquery, MySQLi, Ajax, React JS, and Laravel. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting due to my longtime experience as a Back-office agent.

RELEVANT LINKS

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nemuel-gabitanan-jr-533705276/

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/shirotenshiNmz/

Github: https://github.com/nmgbtnan

Portfolio: https://nmzgbtnanportfolio.vercel.app/

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM Business Services Inc.

UP Ayala Technohub, Quezon City

Imperial Tobacco Group - Master Data Analyst

September 2020 - September 2021

• Master Data and Record-to-Report (R2R) - <u>Updates the list of master data informations and updates the records for the supply and demand of multiple ITG Clients</u> 'all over New Zealand' for the ITG Internal agents to use when processing the request of their clients, and to balance the delivery demands per scheduled resupply of cigars and other merchandise.

AT&T - Flexware Agent

February 2019 - September 2020

• AT&T Flexware – Gatekeeper

 <u>Receives and redistributes all the Flexware Support Requests</u> coming from the On-shore AT&T Flexware Client/Customer Representatives to AT&T Flexware Agents onsite or offshore (Support Request is returned to them if the set requirements prior to their request is incomplete).

• AT&T Flexware – IPFlex

o <u>Handling the configurations for business clients</u> with an internet speed of 10mb to 100mb, exclusively for business branches under a Flexware Device configuration.

• AT&T Flexware Sales Support

- Supporting business clients setups using the AT&T Flexware Device which handles multiple network and security configurations on each of their business branches.
- Scheduling and being the Host/Mediator for Conference Calls between the AT&T Client/Customer Representative and the AT&T Technical Team who will handle the installation of the Flexware device for the business client.

o <u>Configures the Flexware device as per instructions provided</u> from the conference call before releasing to the On-field AT&T Technical Team.

IBM Business Services Inc

Ortigas CBD, Pasig City

AT&T - GOSS agent

July 2017 - February 2019

• AT&T GOSS - IPFlex / EaFlex / IP Toll-Free

Mandling the support request configurations for business clients and high priority business clients with a flexible internet speed of 10mb to 100mb, 100mb to 1000mb, or under an exclusive Toll-Free numbers for their international clients.

KEY SKILLS

Front-End: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, React JS, Bootstrap, NicePage.

Back-End: PHP, Ajax, Laravel

Database: MySQLi.

Online Collaboration Tools: GitHub, Slack, Discord, Cisco WebEx, Zoom, Teamviewer, Google Suite,

Microsoft Office(Teams, Outlook, Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Solo Project

Nems Gabitanan - Portfolio Project Website -

Feb 2024 – Present

- **Tools used:** Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, React JS, EmailJS.
- Non-Dev Tools used: Handbrake video editor.
- Provided the System Analysis and Front-End codes during the web development. (Laravel Back-End in-progress, to be followed up once a web server and domain will be available.)
- Solo development, building the Frontend of my Portfolio website from a mix of scratch/vanilla, and a combination of 2 Web templates online(Tooplate.com), then refactored the whole template to a React JS, Bootstrap, and React-Bootstrap frontend.

KodeGo – FullStack Web Development Bootcamp

MeguMakes Events Souvenir Craft Shop

May 2023 – *August* 2023

- Tools used: Bootstrap, Jquery, Ajax, PHP, MySQLi
- Provided the System Analysis, Front-End and Back-End codes during the web development.
- Solo development, building the Frontend and Backend of a start-up eCommerce website from a mix of scratch/vanilla, and Web templates online(eg. Nicepage).

STI College Fairview Thesis Defence

Computerized Sales and Inventory for Jhastine General Merchandise

June 2014 – October 2014

- Tools used: VB.NET, MySQL.
- Provided the System Analysis, Front-End and Back-End Codes during the Software Development.
- Led a team, building the Frontend and Backend of a Hardware Store eCommerce Software from scratch.

EDUCATION

KodeGo – 917 Ventures(Online Bootcamp)

Bonifacio Global City, Taguig

Full-Stack Web Development

- Graduated as Top 5 of the Online Class.
- **Acquired/Refreshed skills:** HTML, CSS, Java, Jquery, Bootstrap, PHP, Ajax, MySQLi, MySQL with dbhelper setup, React JS, Laravel.

STI College Fairview

North Fairview, Quezon City

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Passed the Thesis Proposal as the group's System Analyst and Lead Programmer.
- Acquired skills: HTML, CSS, Java, PHP, MySQL, VB6, VB.NET.